Using language Reading and listening
The story of Atlanta
Atlanta was a Greek princess.
She was very beautiful and could run faster than any man in Greece.
But she was not allowed to run and win glory for herself in the Olympic Games.
Her father said that she must marry,
so Atlanta made a bargain with him.
She said to him, "These are my rules.
When a man says he wants to marry me,
I will run against him.
If he cannot run as fast as me.
he will be killed.
So many of them sadly went home,
but others stayed to run the race.
There was a man called Hippomenes who was amazed when he heard of Atlanta’s rules, "
Why are these men so foolish?" he thought.
Why will they let themselves be killed because they cannot run as fast as this princess?"
However,
when he saw Atlanta come out of her house to run,
Hippomenes changed his mind.
I will marry Atlanta - or die!" he said.
The race started and although the men ran very fast,
Atlanta ran faster.
As Hippomenes watched he thought, "
How can I run as fast as Atlanta?" He went to ask the Greek Goddess of Love
for help.She promised to help him and gave him three golden apples.
She said, "Throw an apple in front of Atlanta when she is running past.
When she stops to pick it up, you will be able to run past her
and win." Hippomenes took the apples and went to the King.
He said, "I want to marry Atlanta." The King was sad to see another man die,
but Hippomenes said, "I will marry her - or die!" So the race began.